According to the license of IIT,
to maintain the license of IIT, there
are some criteria for the life insurance license which you will have to
fulfill always, such as 12 lives
and a premium of 50%. If we talk about the Life Insurance Company
of India or private sector life insurance
company, then five to 10
policies and a premium of ₹100000 is
mandatory there. You have to do this only then
your license will remain. If you do
not fulfill this criteria then your
IIT license will be terminated.
[Music]
Hello friends, welcome to my
YouTube channel. Friends, I hope you
all are healthy and happy. Friends,
today's video
is on license. Or one of my
followers messaged me yesterday that sir, the
information you are bringing is very
informative, so why don't you tell me the difference between broker
license and ID license.
What is the difference between the two
and what are the benefits of both?
Give detailed information about it so that if we
want to reduce our agency and
this industry on a large scale, then
broker license  We should also know the benefits of it
or how to get a broker license. We
need all this information, so we will
make a video regarding this.
Friends, before starting the video,
I would like to appeal to you that if you
blog on Instagram, belong to the finance
industry,
are a financial advisor, or any other communication company that
deals in insurance or finance
or the banking system, then
all kinds of news related to this, which are the
most updated in the industry,
we bring it to our channel through our videos. So
if you have not subscribed to this channel
yet, then
definitely subscribe to the channel so that
you do
not miss such important updates. If you
subscribe to the channel and hit the bell icon, then
whatever news
comes like this will reach you first. So
friends, thank you very much to everyone who has not subscribed to the channel.
Let's go to
our video, let's talk about
our topic, that is, ID or license,
what is the difference between the two,
friends, here we will talk about ID
and broker license.  There are
benefits as to
how many codes an individual can take, i.e.,
a person can take three codes, in which one is
health insurance, one is life
insurance and one is general insurance,
and this code cannot be taken without ID,
he will have to give the exam of memory,
he will have to give the IIT exam,
after this he can take the code of Idea,
if he has taken the exam of life insurance or general
insurance, then there is
no need for him to give the exam for health insurance,
he will get that code for free without any other
exam, let's talk about broker code,
we call broker code as point of sales, that is, point
of sale means point of
sale, you can take it from any broker company
and there is
no retirement of any exam for any progress in it,
friends, if we talk about its advantage of
broker code, then friends, the biggest
advantage in this is that with the broker code you get the
benefits of all the companies, the
insurance
benefits of all the companies, the policies
of all the companies,  You
can work with a single broker code. The
biggest difference in the broker code ID is that
within a single idea, you have to limit yourself to three companies:
one life, one place, and one
health. And that's where I talk about the broker code. You
can work with all the companies on one platform. In that, your
health is a caste, your jealousy is a caste, and your
life is a caste. According to the iodine code,
you work with three companies.
And here the biggest safety issue is that
your renewal is
granted. This means that
if you are doing proper follow-up of the client
and submitting his premium, then the
renewal is granted and it will be credited to your account.
Now, if we talk about the broker, the
broker renewal is unsafe
because it depends on the broker model and how the
broker structure is for working.
Because if we
look at all the brokers present in the market, there are B2B,
C2B,
and B2B too. So, when you take this broker code, you have to keep in mind
that you are
sitting in the G model. He is a B2B broker.  That is a
B2C broker. Now first of all
we should understand B2B and B2C, what is
this thing,
so B2 wire means that the company will
contact only its advisor, that is, it will have a
B2B relationship, that is, if we
talk about the link, then it will contact the agent directly and
not his customer, so this is called
B2B relationship and a company which is in
contact with its agent,
also contacts the customer, then that company
deals in B2C and also deals in B2B,
here
whichever broker works in the B2C model, there is a greater possibility
of our client knowing your client on the basis of the story or the story
because you must have often
seen that whatever companies work in BTC, they have done
cross selling on the basis of the story or the story
and they have their own team to
pitch the product, so they can release
that story or the story to your customer on your data
and after enriching your customer, they
also prepare your customer for their other product and the story or the story,
that customer can be taken away from your hands, so the
model of this company is also of broker Shiv.  If
you are inside, do not get associated with the company at all.
That Kahaani has the power to protect your interests
and also take your customers away from you.
But the company that is working
there does not have such problems. The company is
professional and
keeps track of its customers as well as its advisors. They know that the advisor
is with me, on this basis the customer is associated with them. There are
some companies
in the market that work in the video. I will
not take any names here because this is
not a pet video of mine, this will be about my
personal experience and I am
making the video on Kahaani based on the request of our followers.
So you will have to research this yourself which
companies work in the B2B model in the market
and which companies
work in the B2C model in the market. Inside Broker Shiv,
where the company's model v2 is also
in Broker Code, there is only one Renwal of yours. That
company does not touch your customers, they ensure the
privacy of their data and they
deal only with business people for their business.  If we talk according to the code, then
as I told you, there are
imitations of three companies, along with Renwal Granted
and Limited Payout, there is also Limited Payout
here because if you see, if we talk about
IND's life insurance, that is, if we
talk about the life segment, if we
talk about life insurance products, then
according to IIT, 25 to 35%
IP out can be given to the agent and the
maximum payout limit here is up
to 45%, it depends on
how much is your business volume and which
contact you are achieving, it
depends on the contact and normally there
is a payout of 25 to 35% only on the life
insurance product.
According to IIT license, to maintain the IIT license, there
are some criteria for the life insurance license which you will
always have to fulfill, like 12 lives
and a premium of Rs. 50, if we talk about the Life
of India and if we talk about the private sector life
company, then five to 10
policies and till now I have
There is a mandatory requirement of Rs. 1 lakh for free. You have to do this only
then your license will be valid. If you do
not fulfill this criteria, then
your ID license will be terminated.
If we talk about the broker
code, as mentioned, there is no need for any exam for the broker code, nor is there any need for any
target for any progress here.
Your options are full with every company to
reduce it. Nothing else is
mandatory here. Friends, if you have
taken the broker code, you will have to fulfill only one
condition that is, after
taking the broker code, you will have to
activate your code by doing business of ₹10,000.
Because obviously, if you have
taken the broker code, then there is a minimum criteria of ₹10,000 for doing your business.
This is also for the time when you took the broker.
After that, there are
no such conditions on this broker code.
Tell me one more special thing about the broker code, as I said, there is
no condition of any kind, there is
no mandatory condition.  To fulfil the target and
if we look at this target
within the broker code, it is the same as in the Live Journal Health Motor, that is, no
one has any separate
power, but if I
talk about Idea License, then
you will have to fulfill different credits in every segment, for
example, after life insurance, you will have to do 12
lives and pay a premium of Rs. 50,
whereas after health insurance,
you will have to put in a minimum of one business every quarter,
and if we
talk about insurance, then there too
you had to fulfill such credits, you will have to keep the
code always active by doing business,
if we do it after the ID of payout in life, then in
life insurance, as
I told, the maximum payout is 25 to 35%,
but if we
talk about broker code, then the payout of live there is
minimum 30% to 45%
and the possibility of maximum is
very high because the
contact there starts only after 32-45,
and in the live product, that is, the
idea one  In the license,
your contact starts after 35, 30, 25 to 30,
so the commission on top of that is
extra. According to the Idiot Code,
if I talk about the payout of health insurance, then the
minimum and maximum
payout here is 15%
and if we compare it with the broker code, then the
minimum health insurance payout in the broker code is
25 to 35% and this can
go up to a maximum of 40% and it depends on
your business and on top of that it depends on the
contact
and that commission is
also credited to your account today.
IIT and it is paid out exactly as per the court
and if I talk then the
payout of IIT is quite limited, whereas if we
talk about the court then the
payout of broker code is quite handsome, that is,
if we see then it is good
and the contact is different, without it, then
there it starts at 250  It
happens and the maximum goes up to 15-18. If we
talk about broker code under general insurance then it goes up to 30, 40, 45, even
60, 70 if we
talk about commercial vehicle or commercial property. There are
some conditions for making IIT code and broker code.
As I said, there is
no such thing as condition in the court, but if we talk about
IIT code, where we
talk about renewal, there are many
conditions imposed. If
we talk about health insurance, then
according to the idea and
according to the companies, you have to enter a business every quarter, only then
you
can maintain your revenue, otherwise your revenue will
also appear to be declining and
your code is maintained at some basic level.
If your health insurance code
and the claims in it are very high then the
company can terminate your agency there also.
If by mistake you are
accused of fraud, then your agency can
end there and your business for the whole year.  It
can become absolutely zero because
after that you will become a terminator, then
you will not get any kind of benefit from ringworm. It is
also
seen that if your quarterly
business is not getting updated and you do
not activate your code, then the companies start downgrading your renal
percentage, it
depends on the volume of your business.
So if you have an Idea
code, then friends, you have to keep in mind
how to reduce it from the ID code. If you are
interested in broker code, then friends,
you have to do complete research on which companies
reduce broker code in the broker model, only then
you can Jain. And one more
thing to note is that if you have an
Idea license, then you
cannot apply for a broker because the broker code is the
same as the relation who does not have the ID license. So,
you
can transfer the broker code to a family member
so that you can get the option. But let me
tell you some good news, as we had
talked about in the old video that if our insurance
Shubham portal starts  If it goes,
we probably won't even need a broker code,
and we'll find plenty of options
there with broker codes. And the
thing about that will be a
little bit on the story because the broker code, the
insurance portal option available
on the story,
is certified by IIT, so its certification will be
by IIT only. And these broker codes are the
model of private companies,
so this story
definitely does a little bit of manipulation within the story,
looking at business upon business. Friends, Amit, I'm giving
you information about people
and if you want more information, then friends,
please like the video and subscribe to the channel.
Friends, and if
you have any query or
doubt about any kind of thing, you can call me on my WhatsApp number.
My
WhatsApp number is in the description. You can call me there
and also comment. And
if you want to know something on any other topic or want a video,
please write to me in the comment box,
and I'll try to
bring you a video on this topic as soon as possible.  So
friends, thank you very much to all of you for watching this video. We will meet
in the next video with the next topic. Till then,
Namaskar, Jai Hind, Jai Bharat.